本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯&校對&時間軸：醉芝士
后期&總監：魚骨頭
八十年代  對所有青春期的男生來說
In the '80s, a defining moment
一個關鍵性時刻  就是看《空手道小子》
for every teenage boys was seeing "The Karate Kid".
這部電影在我們的心上拳打腳踢
It kicked and punched and swept the
再加個掃堂腿
leg of our hearts.
沒人比我哥巴瑞更愛這部電影
No one loved it more than my brother Barry.
上吧
Come at me!
上截  蛇形
High block! Cobra strike!
向左虛晃  向右  忍者打滾
Fake left, go right. Ninja roll!
沒事  我沒事
It's okay. I'm okay.
現在來個掌劈
Now throw a chop!
我截住了掌劈
I block that chop!
回擊  高踢  憤怒之拳
I retaliate! High kick! Fist of fury!
致命一擊
Death blow!
我在想
Hmm, you know, I was thinking--
你不把招數先說出來會好些吧
It might be better if you didn't call out your moves first.
好主意
That's a great idea.
偷襲
Sneak attack!
當然  我哥自認為技藝高超
Sure, my big bro had an inflated sense of skill,
但在我家  把他吹上天的是我媽
but in my house, my mother was the one who did the inflating.
她戴著我們所謂的"母親護目鏡"
She wore something we called "mom goggles."
這讓她覺得我們做的事
They made everything we did
不是好  而是好到爆
not just good, but spectacular.
瞧你  我的小功夫大師
Oh, look at you, my little kung fu master!
這不是功夫  停下
It's not kung fu. Stop!
這是空手道
I do kara-te.
功夫加上空手道  而且好危險
Bilingual and dangerous?
你真是太厲害了  寶貝
Oh, you are just off-the-charts amazing, honey.
大多數孩子會無視母親的表揚
Most kids ignore their mom's high praise...
但巴瑞不是大多數孩子
But Barry wasn't most kids.
他真的相信老媽那些天花亂墜的話
He really believed the hype.
遺憾的是  面對女生時  他的自信
Unfortunately, that confidence did not translate
無法變為行動
to his moves with the ladies.
你好
Hi?
好啊
Yo.
橫劈儲物柜
Locker strike!
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
我很好  我的手像石頭一樣堅硬
I'm fine. My hands are like rocks.
但同時很柔軟  又溫柔
But they're soft, too. And gentle.
像鴨寶寶一樣
Like baby ducks.
-怪人  -好了  孩子們
- Weird. - All right, kids!
又到了這個時候了
That time of year again.
假日才藝表演  怎么樣
Holiday talent show. Eh?
有人嗎
Nobody?
老天  我愛死才藝表演了
Oh, my god, I love the talent show.
是真的嗎
Oh, do ya now?
Do ya now?
怪人
Weird.
你真好
You're great.
回頭見
See ya later.
巴瑞有了計劃
Barry had a plan in motion,
當晚  他實施了計劃
and that night, he put it into action.
晚上好
Good evening.
很高興大家今晚都在
Glad you could all make it tonight.
-什么意思  -重大消息要宣布
- What--what is this? - Big announcement.
我決定在學校的才藝表演上
I've decided to do a kara-teroutine
來一段空手道
at the school talent show.
面試在明天
Auditions are tomorrow.
我不想說得太過夸張
Now I don't want to make too big a deal out of this,
但我相信  這將是有史以來
but I do believe it will be the greatest moment
最偉大的時刻
in the history of everything.
我的天  這主意太棒了
Oh, my goodness! What a wonderful idea!
默里  這是不是非常棒的主意
Murray, isn't this a wonderful idea?
如果我同意  是否能不再發表意見了
If I say yes, can I be out of the conversation?
那你呢  愛麗卡
What about you, Erica?
你一定得去參加這個才藝表演
You should absolutely do this talent thing.
我聽到你在沖澡時唱佩特·貝納通的歌
I've heard you singing Pat Benetton in the shower.
放心吧  我會去參加才藝表演的
Don't worry, guys. I'll be at the talent show--
坐在第一排
In the front row.
因為我和朋友們總是喜歡大笑一場
'Cause my friends and I always go for a good laugh.
去吧  帶上你所有的漂亮朋友
Go ahead! Bring all your hot friends.
我會用絕招讓她們高聲喝彩的
I'll wow 'em with my moves.
亞當  沖我的臉上扔個餐包
Now, Adam, chuck a dinner roll at my face.
看著我把它劈開  來吧
Watch me deflect it. Come on.
不  不是這樣  溫柔一點
No. No. Not like that. Gentle.
別打我的臉  如果你可以...
And don't hit me in the face if you can--
-不  你在做什么  -溫柔些
- No--what are doing?! - Gently.
-讓我準備好  來吧  -住手
- Let me get ready, okay? Come on. - Stop it!
太棒了
Yes!
-搞什么  -像閃電一樣  我愛閃電
- What the hell? - Like lightning! I'm like lightning!
我知道你可以的  我知道你可以的
I knew you could do it! I knew you could do it!
那是一九八幾年的12月9日
It was December 9th, 1980-something,
巴瑞的假日好心情完全不見蹤影
and Barry's holiday cheer was nowhere in sight.
這一切有什么意義
What's the point of anything?!
冷靜  慢著  出什么事了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down. What's wrong?
-才藝表演不要我  -我不明白
- I didn't get into the talent show. - I don't understand.
-他們拒絕了我  -完全沒道理
- They rejected me. - That literally makes no sense.
面試的人  除了我全選上了
Everyone who auditioned got in but me.
我聽到你的話了
I hear what you're saying,
但我完全沒聽明白
but I cannot wrap my mind around that.
格拉斯科特老師說我的表演太不合適了
Mr. Glascott said my routine was too inappropriate.
做一個完美的空手道天使是怎么不合適了
How is being a perfect kara-te angel inappropriate?
巴瑞  我想過了
Barry! Okay, I have been thinking.
你的空手道表演
Your kara-te routine--
需要專業的導演
It needs a professional director.
就是我  創意無限的人
That's me! A big idea guy.
而且  我看過太多空手道電影了
Plus, I've seen a million karate movies.
你在哭嗎
Are you crying?
沒有  沒有
No. No!
這是勇士的眼淚  沒關系了
They're warrior's tears, and it doesn't matter!
學校說不行
The school said no!
我永遠不會出蛇形了
I'll never cobra strike again!
真不公平
This isn't fair!
在那一刻  我媽媽的腦子里
At that moment, there was only one thing
只有一個主意
running through my mom's mind.
沒人有資格告訴我的寶貝  他不能出蛇形
No one tells my baby he can't cobra strike.
格拉斯科特老師
Mr. Glascott!
我需要現在和你談談
I need to speak to you immediately.
不好意思  我和數學俱樂部的孩子
Oh, I'm sorry. I have an important morning meeting
有個重要的早會
with the kids from the math club.
書呆子可以等等
The nerds can wait.
我兒子巴瑞·金伯格等不了
My son--Barry Goldberg--cannot.
你是  貝弗莉·金伯格嗎
Are you... Beverly Goldberg?
正是在下
Oh, yes, I am.
告訴我  什么樣的教育工作者
Tell me, what kind of educator
會踐踏學生的夢想
stomps on the dreams of his students?
巴瑞是個好孩子
Look, Barry's a good kid,
所以我才勸他不要
which is kinda why I discouraged him
參加才藝表演
from taking part in the show.
這里有些萬千寵愛在一身的學生
See, some of the more high-profile students here
是非常苛刻的  你懂吧
can be very critical, if you follow me.
真不懂
I really don't.
這里出風頭的孩子都是混蛋
The popular kids here are real douche-sacks.
去年  有個孩子表演了一段不錯的腹語
Last year, one kid did a lovely ventriloquist act.
那些孩子  他們在表演后對腹語木偶
The kids--well, they did unspeakable things
做了些我說不出口的事
to that doll after the show.
說實話  非常的過分
Quite frankly, it was very jarring.
巴瑞的空手道表演
And Barry's karate is really ripe
正是他們嘲弄的對象
for that type of ridicule.
這里是高中  不是《搜尋明日之星》
Uh, this is high school, not "Star Search."
[著名節目主持人]
誰死了你才坐上麥克馬洪的位置
I mean, who died and made you Ed Mcmahon?
約翰遜老師  我們的體育老師
Mr. Johansson. Our gym teacher.
他去世了
He died.
這不重要  巴瑞要上表演
Yeah, it doesn't matter. Barry is doing that show.
我會不計一切代價
I will go to the top on this.
我會向校長請愿  還有學校董事會
I'll petition the principal, the school board,
監管人  市長辦公室
the superintendent, the mayor's office,
萬不得已  教育部部長
the U.S. Secretary of education if I have to.
怎么樣  安德魯
So what's it gonna be, Andre?
你知道我的名字
You know my name.
我什么都知道
I know everything.
我被選上參加才藝表演了
I got into the talent show!
好消息  我好意外
That's good news, and very surprising to me.
格拉斯科特老師說三州才藝表演委員會
Mr. Glascott said the tri-state talent show committee
開會裁決空手道是一種藝術形式
met and ruled that kara-te is an art form.
三州才藝表演委員會會議
Wow, the tri-state talent show committee met.
幾乎令人無法相信啊
You know, that's almost unbelievable!
這是事實  別再糾結了
Well, it happened, so let's just move on.
我們又回來了
Oh, man, we're back in business!
快做正經事
Let's get to work!
我去拿雙節棍和爆竹
I'll go get my nunchucks and firecrackers.
不準用爆竹
No firecrackers!
這么說  你威脅了一位老師
So... You threatened a teacher?
拜托  我只是客氣地建議
Please. I just gently suggested
他照我說的做
that he do what I say,
否則會有可怕的后果
or there'd be dire consequences.
為什么每次咱家孩子在學校不順心
Why is it you go trotting down to the school
你就要殺到學校去
and yell at somebody every time one of our kids
把某人吼一頓
doesn't get their way?
我關心他們的成長  這是好事
I'm involved. That's a good thing.
-你失控了  -我別無選擇  默里
- You are out of control! - I had no choice, Murray.
你見過巴瑞玩空手道嗎
Have you even seen Barry do kara-te?
就像是美麗的芭蕾
It's like a beautiful ballet,
只是途中不斷出拳咕嚕  還有滾來滾去
but with punching and grunting and rolling around.
上了八堂課他就退出了
He quit after eight lessons
因為他不想騎自行車去六條街外的教室
because he didn't want to bike the six blocks to get there.
這算是哪門子的查克·諾里斯[世界空手道冠軍]
It hardly makes him Chuck Norris.
-是嗎  巴瑞  過來  -什么事
- Oh, really? Barry, get in here. - What?
你父親想在表演之前
Your father would like a sneak peek
先睹為快
of your routine before the big show.
亞當  去拿爆竹
Adam, get the firecrackers.
-不準用爆竹  -不用爆竹
- No firecrackers! - No firecrackers.
龍形身法  咿呀
Dragon stance! Kee-ya!
虎爪  咿呀
Tiger claw! Kee-ya!
相撲戰斧砍
Sumo tomahawk chop!
咿呀
Kee-ya!
助手  呈上兵器
Assistant. Present weaponry.
雙節棍
Nunchucks!
Nunchucks.
沒事  我沒事
That's okay. I'm okay.
金箍棒
Bo staff!
抱歉
Sorry.
現在
And now...
最致命的武器  我的雙拳
The most deadly weapon of 'em all--my hands.
不好  打劫
Oh, no! A robber!
別擔心  凱莉·勒布洛克  我來救你
Don't worry, Kelly Lebrock, I'll save you!
[著名女影星]
不  不是這樣
No--oh-- don't!
你不應該打我
You're not supposed to hit me.
放下武器  亞當
Disarm! Adam!
老天  你應該放下武器
Jeez, you're supposed to disarm.
你應該放手
You're supposed to let go!
他已經被解除武器了
He has been disarmed!
現在  壓軸戲
And now... The big finish.
該死
Damn!
在表演時會碎的
That'll break during the show.
我這輩子從來沒見過
That was the greatest thing
這么精彩的表演
my eyeballs have ever, ever seen!
-要我再來一次嗎  -太好了
- Do you want me to go again? - Yes!
我們再來一遍
We're going again!
原來  不是所有父母都戴著"母親護目鏡"的
Turns out, not everyone had mom goggles.
再來一遍  再來一遍
Do it again! Do it again!
愛麗卡完全不關心
The talent show was the furthest thing
才藝表演  但老爺子希望改變這點
from Erica's mind, but Pops was hoping to change that.
孩子  不介意我坐一會兒吧
Hey, kiddo, mind if I sit down?
我知道你要說什么
I know what you're gonna say,
我不會參加才藝表演的
and I'm not doing the talent show.
我不是為這個來的
That's not why I'm here.
我是來  借雜志的
I came to... Borrow this magazine.
追猛男的八招
"Eight ways to catch a hunk."
這是什么垃圾
What is this garbage?
既然你自己說了
But since you brought it up--
老爺子  算了吧
Pops, forget it!
參加才藝表演  無異于社交自殺
Doing the talent show is social suicide.
我還不如走上舞臺
I might as well go up on stage
拿著塊寫著"我有虱子"的牌子
with a sign that says, "I have lice."
這種表演可不行
That doesn't sound like much of an act.
你有一副好嗓子
Come on, you have an amazing voice,
你彈得一手好吉他
a-and you're terrific on the guitar.
你得彈奏吉他
You got to play the guitar.
沒辦法  賣了
Can't. Sold it.
什么  你很喜歡那把吉他
What?! You loved that guitar.
現在我很喜歡我的皮外套
And now I love my leather jacket.
這話讓人惱火
That is very angering.
我很感謝你這么相信我
Look, I appreciate you believing in me
什么什么的  但讓我參加才藝表演
and all that crap, but there's no chance
絕對沒機會
I'm gonna do the talent show.
有機會的
Oh, there's a chance,
因為我會讓你參加的
'Cause I'm gonna get you to do it.
不可能的
Uh, not gonna happen!
走著瞧
We'll see!
浪費時間
Waste of time!
聽不到啦
Can't hear you!
早上好  小巴  這身空手道睡衣真不錯
Good morning, Bar. Nice karate pajamas.
這個叫空手道服
It's called a gi.
你得受點教育了  多看些電影吧
You need to educate yourself, man. See more movies.
我知道你媽媽喜歡這套香港的咿咿呀呀
Listen, I know your mom loves this whole Hong Kong fooey act,
但是  你有沒有考慮過做點別的
but... Haven't you considered doing something else?
-我為什么要這樣  -因為你是巴瑞·金伯格
- Why would I ever do that? - Because you're Barry Goldberg,
有許多不同才藝的人
a man of many different talents.
這倒是真的  我擅長的事多了
It's true. I am great at a lot of stuff.
滑板  饒舌  霹靂舞
Skateboarding, rapping, breakdancing.
再來點
A little...
街舞
Pop-and-lock action.
我們為什么要說這個
Why are we even having this conversation?
我要表演空手道
I'm going kara-te.
委員會的裁決對我有利
The committee ruled in my favor.
巴瑞  你不能表演這個  我是過來人
Barry, you can't do this act. I speak from experience.
你說什么呢
What are you talking about?
我在你這么大的時候
When I was your age,
我是橄欖球隊中最搞笑的人
I was the funniest guy on the football team.
搞笑  你什么時候搞笑過
Funny? Since when are you funny?
我相當搞笑
I'm plenty funny, okay?
我是個開心果
I was hilarious.
我喜歡講黃段子
I used to tell dirty jokes,
我用毛巾拍隊友屁屁
I'd snap guys with a towel.
我給所有人取綽號
I gave everybody a nickname,
比如說  小白臉和小個子
like, uh, pretty boy and shorty.
這些綽號太糟糕了
Those are terrible nicknames.
小個子長得并不矮
Shorty wasn't short.
事實上  他非常高
As a matter of fact, he was a giant.
我的天  腺體出了問題
Oh, my god. Had a gland problem.
挺讓人傷心的
Actually sad stuff.
-你想說什么  -我想說
- What's the point to this? - The point is,
教練說  默里  你是個人物
the coach said, "Murray, you're a card.
去主持賽前動員大會吧
Why don't you host the pep rally?"
我去了
So I did.
我上臺后  意識到
I get up there, I realize
我只能講上一分鐘
I've only got one minute of material.
一分鐘
One minute!
我在全校面前傻眼了
I bombed in front of the whole school.
-他們沖我扔桃子  -他們為什么有桃子
- They threw peaches at me. - Why'd they have peaches?
不知道  當時根本不是桃子上市的季節
I don't know! They weren't even in season!
我只知道  我不想你經歷
All I know is, I don't want you to go through
我經歷的這一切
what I went through.
請別表演  我求你了
Please don't do your act. I'm begging you!
這么說你覺得我的表演會砸
So you think I'm gonna suck?
不是  兒子
No, son.
我知道你會砸
I know you're going to suck.
我有話告訴你
Well, I got news for you.
觀眾不會扔桃子
The audience won't throw peaches.
他們會扔鮮花
They'll throw flowers.
喝彩  咪咪
And cheers! And boobs!
赤裸裸的咪咪  到處都是
Naked boobs! Everywhere!
你走著瞧  走著瞧
Just you watch. Watch!
咪咪  赤裸裸的咪咪
Boobs! Naked!
在那一刻  我爸意識到
In that moment, my dad realized
他只有一個辦法來保護巴瑞
he only had one way to protect Barry.
他要通過阻止他
He was gonna stand up for his son
來支持他
by standing in his way.
格拉斯科特老師嗎
Mr. Glascott?
我們需要談談
We need to talk.
-我又被刷下來了  -什么
- I'm out again! - What?!
格拉斯科特老師說  國家才藝表演委員會
Mr. Glascott said the natial talent show committee
推翻了三州才藝表演委員會的裁決
overruled the tri-state talent show committee.
這真是令人驚訝
Well, this is very surprising
無法接受  但他們已經裁決了
and unacceptable, but they have made their ruling,
我相信我們應該尊重他們的決定
and I believe we should honor it.
這個國家的才藝表演委員會制度已經沒救了
The talent show committee system in this country's broken!
國家委員會
National committee, huh?
它的權力比三州委員會大
Well, it's more powerful than the tri-state committee.
-我能怎么說  -難以置信
- What can I say? - This is unbelievable.
你對我的行為指手畫腳一番后
You trotted down to that school
自己又殺到了學校嗎
after being so judgy with me about it?
我只是做個關心孩子成長的家長
Hey, I'm just being an involved parent.
你告訴我  這是好事
You told me that was a good thing.
你做就是壞事  你讓自己的兒子
Not when you do it. You got your own son
被踢出了才藝表演  誰會這樣做啊
kicked out of a talent show. Who does that?
我這是為了孩子好
Look, I'm doing the kid a favor
我沒有一直戴著"母親護目鏡"
by not wearing mom goggles all the time.
-母親什么  -護目鏡
- Mom what? - Goggles!
我們都知道你一直戴著
We all know you wear 'em!
這讓你覺得咱家的孩子好聰明
It makes you think our kids are so brilliant
好完美  拉的屎都是彩虹色的
and perfect and poop rainbows.
哪怕一次  拜托你取下"母親護目鏡"
For once, just take those mom goggles off
承認咱們的能干孩子們
and admit that our wonderful children
在許多事上都是不行的
are terrible at so many different things.
我不會
I will not.
他們這輩子
They're gonna have plenty of people
會有許多人想要打擊他們
trying to tear them down in life,
只要他們還在我的屋檐下
so while they're under my roof,
我至少能做的就是幫他們建立自信
the least I can do is try to build them up.
接受咱們孩子是庸才的事實吧
Accept our children's mediocrity!
這是種解脫
It's freeing!
你不是吧  當我不存在嗎
Seriously? I'm right here!
不是說你  你棒極了
Oh, not--not you. You're fantastic.
是啊  你自己也是個活寶
Yeah, you're a real gem yourself.
隨著才藝表演的臨近
As the talent show drew near,
老爺子覺得是時候拿出秘密武器了
Pops thought it was time to pull out his secret weapon.
你好  我
Hello. I...
我不知道你在這里
I didn't realize you were here.
我只是坐在這里
Me, I'm just sitting here,
休息下  彈奏下班卓琴
relaxing, strumming the old banjo.
你彈了也白彈
You're wasting your strums.
是嗎  還是說是時候溫習下
Am I? Or is it time to do that duet
以前的二重唱
we used to do?
你不回家嗎  比爾·貝莉
Won't you come home, Bill Bailey?
老爺子  老爺子
Pops. Pops!
我不會參加才藝表演的
I'm not doing the talent show.
求你了  參加吧
Come on! Do this show!
我甚至可以把班卓琴借給你
You can even borrow my banjo.
別誤會
Don't take this the wrong way,
但在舞臺上拿著把班卓琴
but toting a banjo up on stage
可不能算作酷
isn't exactly what you'd call cool.
什么時候開始班卓琴都不算酷了
Since when is the banjo not cool?
從班卓琴被發明開始
Since the invention of the banjo.
愛麗卡  你小的時候  什么都參加
Erica, when you were younger, you used to do everything--
排球  體操  校合唱團
Volleyball, gymnastics, school chorus.
你這是怎么啦
What happened to you?
我上高中了  這里會有人對你指手畫腳
Well, I go to high school, where people judge you.
如果你覺得班卓琴不算酷
Well, if you don't think the banjo's cool,
我還可以拿手風琴
I can always break out the accordion.
結果  老爺子不是唯一一個
Turns out Pops wasn't the only one
想讓金伯格家的孩子上才藝表演的
still trying to get a Goldberg into the talent show.
或是被踢出才藝表演
Or out of the talent show.
別擋道  白癡
Get out of the way, idiot!
你來這里做什么
What are you doing here?
阻止你做你要做的事
Stopping you from doing what you're doing!
我來這里唯一要做的是
The only thing I'm here to do is...
向左虛晃  向右
Fake left, go right.
鼓勵有才藝的學生
But isn't it your responsibility
-不是你的責任嗎  -爸
- to encourage talented students-- - Dad?!
我只是跟格拉斯科特老師說
Oh, hey. I-I was just talking to Mr. Glascott here
讓愛麗卡參加才藝表演
about putting Erica into the talent show.
我受不了了
I can't take this anymore.
你們想要孩子參加  他們能參加
You want your kids in, they're in.
太棒了  哪一個孩子
Oh, great! Which one?
我不知道  兩個都參加  都不參加
I don't know. Both of them? None of them?
我真的不在乎
I really don't care! I mean,
這只是一個愚蠢的高中才藝表演
it's a stupid freakin' high school talent show!
我一時心軟
I had one moment of weakness
想幫你們的兒子一把
where I tried to do something kind for your son.
我道歉
I apologize!
現在我只關心
All I care about now
我還欠著兩萬的學生貸款
is that I owe 20 grand in student loans,
我住的是一個小單間
I live in a studio apartment
下面是一個熱烘烘的干洗店
above a steaming hot dry cleaner,
我的副業是送披薩
and I have a second job where I work as a pizza man,
偶爾我還送披薩
and occasionally I get to deliver pizzas
到學生家里
to my students.
而且我還有一只甩不掉的鸚鵡
Oh, also I have a parrot that I can't get rid of.
鸚鵡能活80年  你們知道嗎
They live for 80 years. Did you know that?
沒人告訴你這個
Nobody tells you about that.
你得把它們寫進遺囑
You have to put them in your will!
真是噩夢
It's a nightmare!
你們想怎樣都行
So, yeah, do whatever you want to do,
因為我真的不在乎
'Cause I really don't care!
我想吃披薩了
That made me hungry for pizza.
誰要吃披薩
Who wants pizza?
叫你們來
All right, we've gathered you here
是因為我們有好消息
because we've got some great news.
才藝表演有變化
There's been some movement on the talent show.
又來  嫌我們大悲大喜還不夠嗎
Again? This has been an emotional roller coaster.
原來  巴瑞可以參加表演
Turns out Barry can do the show!
你不想的話  可以不去
Or not, if you don't want to.
說什么呢
What are you talking about?
國家才藝表演委員會已經裁決了
The national talent show committee already ruled.
這是有法律約束力的
It's binding.
事實上
Actually, um...
-我們就是委員會  -什么
- We're the committees. - What?
你母親自作主張
Your mother took it upon herself
在你沒被選上參加才藝表演時
to trot on down to the high school
殺到學校
and yell at Mr. Glascott
-吼了格拉斯科特老師一頓  -什么
- when you didn't get into the talent show. - What?!
你父親也殺去了
Your father trotted, too.
至少我是想讓他參加表演
At least I was trying to get him into the show.
難以置信  為什么大家都要殺到哪里去
Unbelievable! Why is anyone trotting anywhere?!
一線光明就是  愛麗卡也可以參加表演
The silver lining? Erica's in the show, too.
你說什么
Excuse me?
我跟格拉斯科特老師談過了  他問題多多
I talked to Mr. Glascott. Troubled man.
但我跟他說了你的事
But I told him all about you.
你跟他說點別的吧
Well, you can tell him something else.
我不會參加表演的
I'm not doing that show.
我也不會
Me, too!
因為媽媽插手了  我不會再參加表演了
'Cause mom meddled, I'm not doing that show anymore!
因為爸爸不相信我
And 'cause dad doesn't believe in me,
我要證明你錯了  我會參加表演
I'm gonna prove you wrong, and I'm gonna do the show.
等等  你到底參不參加
Wait. Wh-which one is it?
我不知道
I don't know!
我太生你們兩個的氣了
I'm just so angry at both of you.
我真的覺得你應該參加
I really think you should do it.
好吧  我和亞當談過了
All right. I spoke with Adam.
這事對許多人來說太重要了
This thing matters a lot to a lot of people.
我會參加
I'm back in.
才藝表演又提上了日程
The talent show was back on,
我的導演作品初登場也一樣
and so was my directorial debut!
威廉·佩恩高中的
It was only the opening act
假日才藝表演才開始第一個節目
of the William Penn Academy holiday talent show,
巴瑞就已經怯場了
and Barry was already getting cold feet.
他們好厲害
They're really good.
想要媲美太難了
It's gonna be a tough act to follow.
你擔心什么  你有黑帶
What are you worried about? You got a black belt.
這是從老爸的浴袍上拿下來的
That I took from dad's bathrobe!
呆子
Dorks!
那一刻  巴瑞明白了
In that moment, Barry realized
為什么拉克茜·布魯姆喜歡看才藝表演
the reason why Lexy Bloom loved the talent show.
和其他那些酷孩子一樣
Like the rest of the cool crowd,
她可以嘲笑舞臺上的所有白癡
she could bag on all the idiots on stage.
-我不能上舞臺  -什么
- I can't go out there! - What?!
我做不到  爸爸說得對
I can't do it! Dad was right.
我只會讓自己丟臉
I'm gonna humiliate myself.
他們會沖我扔桃子的
They're gonna throw peaches at me!
桃子  誰有桃子  你說什么呢
Peaches? Who has peaches? What are you talking about?
我做不到
I can't do it!
盡管老爺子做了最大的努力
Despite Pops' best efforts,
愛麗卡卻連才藝表演都沒去
Erica decided to not even go to the talent show.
但咱們的外公  還有一張王牌
But our grandfather had one more card to play.
別想著酷  做自己就好  老爺子贈
這是倒數第二個節目
And that was our second-to-last act,
埃倫·麥克雷表演雜耍
Ellen Mcrae juggling!
好了  空手道小子  下一個到你
All right, karate kid, you're up next.
我不能出去
I can't go out there.
說什么呢  你是壓軸節目
What are you talking about? You're our closer.
得有壓軸節目才行
We gotta have a closer.
或者我直接宣布結束也行
Or I could just end it.
我不參加了
Well, I'm out.
我參加
I'm in.
我外公說也許我能上場
My grandfather said you might have a spot open for me.
既然我完全不在乎  是的
Well, seeing as I don't care at all, yes.
金伯格家的
One of the Goldbergs.
那么
So, um...
這是我沖澡時喜歡唱的歌
This is a song I sing in the shower.
快點唱完了事吧
Just get it over with, I guess.
你是個無情的人  有著不羈的過去
Oh, you're a real tough cookie with the long history
碎掉顆顆芳心  我心也唏噓不已
Of breakin' little hearts like the one in me
一切都沒關系  看你這次如何出擊
That's okay, let's see how you do it
舉起你的雙拳  我們直入正題
Put up your dukes, let's get down to it
你放馬過來
Hit me with your best shot
你盡管放馬過來吧
Why don't you hit me with your best shot?
你放馬過來
Oh, hit me with your best shot
出絕招吧
Fire away
你上來一句"來吧"
You come on with your "come on"
并不光明正大
You don't fight fair
但是沒關系  我并不在乎
But that's okay, just see if I care
打倒我  一切都是徒勞
Knock me down, it's all in vain
我會重新振作起來
I'll get back up on my feet again
你放馬過來
Hit me with your best shot
你盡管放馬過來吧
Why don't you hit me with your best shot?
你放馬過來
Oh, hit me with your best shot
出絕招吧
Fire away
-我要參加  -還是不在乎
- I'm back in! - Still don't care.
你是個無情的人  有著不羈的過去
You're a real tough cookie with the long history
碎掉顆顆芳心
Of breakin' little hearts
我心也唏噓不已
Like the one in me
一切都沒關系  看你這次如何出擊
That's okay, let's see how you do it
舉起你的雙拳  我們直入正題
Put up your dukes, let's get down to it
你放馬過來
Hit me with your best shot
偷襲
Sneak attack!
你盡管放馬過來吧
Why don't you hit me with your best shot?
你放馬過來
Hit me with your best shot
出絕招吧
Fire away
我的寶貝
My babies!
你放馬過來
Hit me with your best shot
你盡管放馬過來吧
Why don't you hit me with your best shot?
你放馬過來
Hit me with your best shot
你可以的  寶貝
You can do it, baby!
老爺子是對的
Pops was right.
沒什么可以令愛麗卡不好意思的
Erica had nothing to be embarrassed about.
事實上在那一刻  作為金伯格一分子
In fact, in that moment, it felt damn good
感覺好極了
to be a Goldberg.
我家孩子是全世界最有才藝的
I have the most talented kids in the world!
比你們家的強多了  比你們家的強多了
More talented than yours! More talented than yours!
-冷靜  冷靜  -我的天
- Calm down. Calm down. - Oh, my god!
尤其對我爸來說  他這輩子第一次
Especially for my dad, who put on the mom goggles...
戴上"母親護目鏡"
for the first time in his life.
太棒了  太棒了
Yeah! Yeah...
謝謝大家
Thank you, guys.
至于我  我做了所有優秀導演會做的事
And as for me, I did what any good director would do--
讓我的明星閃閃發光
I made my star look good.
咿呀
Kee-ya.
我把巴瑞的木板換成了軟木
I switched Barry's board for balsa wood.
獻給教會我空手道的哥哥
媽媽  下一次才藝表演只剩一年時間了
Okay, mom. Next talent show's only a year away.
越早開始準備越好  給我露兩手
Can't start preparing too early! Show me what you got.
我寫了首慢板抒情靈樂
I wrote a smooth soul jam.
準備好了嗎
You ready?
女孩
Girl
我要和你在一起
I want to get with you
大甜甜要和你在一起
Big tasty wants to get with you
你得  嗯  退后
You got to, mmm, back it up
嗯  再退后
Mmm, back it up
不好意思  這是巴瑞·金伯格
I'm sorry, was that Barry Goldberg,
還是巴瑞·曼尼洛  我沒覺得有區別
or Barry Manilow? 'cause I can't tell the difference!
[浪漫歌王]
見鬼
Crap!